<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science FM Hub – Education</title>
    <link>/docs/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Science FM Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="/docs/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Diversity, Equity and Inclusion (DEI) Plan</title>
      <link>/docs/education/diversity-equity-inclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/education/diversity-equity-inclusion/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page contains the Diversity, Equity and Inclusion (DEI) Plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over its first two hundred years, the University of Virginia has been
at the forefront of producing global citizen leaders, groundbreaking
research and scholarship, and world-class patient care. As the
University enters its third century, we continuously seek to define
and redefine ourselves, motivated by our shared passion for discovery,
innovation, community, service, and social justice. One of the
University&amp;rsquo;s top priorities is to create a living, learning, and work
environment that supports&amp;mdash;and challenges&amp;mdash;our academic
community. To achieve its mission, the University must be a place in
which all faculty, students, and staff are active participants in its
work, where those groups historically excluded from participation in
University life are present in numbers that prevent isolation of the
spirit and of the mind, and where each individual is conscious of how
they contribute to the creation and dissemination of knowledge that
enhances the well-being of our community, our state, our nation, and
the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listed below are specific details about how the University of Virginia
(UVA) is engaging in a meaningful way with respect to DEI, as well as
the project plans to ensure that historically underrepresented groups
are a collaborative part of our project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusion of persons from groups underrepresented in STEM as PI, co-PI, and/or senior personnel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UVA seeks to hire persons from underrepresented groups and will seek
representative applicants for the senior personnel in this effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UVA&amp;rsquo;s diversity action plan includes actions steps and metrics
to provide training and support to create processes that mitigate
bias and are more equitable and inclusive. In 2021, the University
created an Inclusive Excellence Planning Committee to assess
inclusivity, which suggested regular professional development
opportunities to all provost office units (including the
Biocomplexity Institute), and to offer leadership development
opportunities around diversity, equity and inclusion. UVA has a goal
of attracting and retaining greater numbers of individuals from
underrepresented populations. UVA&amp;rsquo;s Racial Equity Task Force (RETF)
aligned initiatives with the University&#39;s Inclusive Excellence
framework and the University&#39;s 2030 Strategic Plan to orient and
embed the initiatives in the institutional operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentoring and support programs to increase retention include the
Division for Diversity, Equity and Inclusion at the UVA, which
provides outreach, resources, and support for inclusive hiring
practices for departments and faculty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusion of persons from groups underrepresented in STEM as student researchers or post-doctoral researchers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will seek representative applicants for the postdoctoral position
in this effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Office of Diversity Programs at UVA cultivates a rich, inclusive
and supportive learning environment, where the identities,
perspectives, and views of all graduate students and postdoctoral
scholars are affirmed to establish dignity and pride to thrive at
the University of Virginia. The Office of Diversity Programs is a
subsidiary of the Office of Graduate and Postdoctoral Affairs (OGPA)
and serves as a resource hub for information to connect students,
staff, and faculty to opportunities by offering recruitment and
retention, developmental training, and community engagement and
outreach programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhancement/collaboration with existing diversity programs at your home organization and/or nearby organizations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Virginia&amp;rsquo;s Racial Equity Task Force (RETF) aligned initiatives with the University&#39;s Inclusive Excellence framework and the University&#39;s 2030 Strategic Plan to orient and embed the initiatives in the institutional operations. The Division for Diversity, Equity and Inclusion office at the University of Virginia offers training on education and prevention related to discrimination and harassment, sexual misconduct, mandated reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;University efforts located in or benefiting underserved communities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Center for Community Partnerships at University of Virginia
serves as both a front door to the University for community members
and a collaborative space for UVA&amp;rsquo;s existing community efforts. The
center is anchored by UVA&amp;rsquo;s Equity Center, and is staffed by members
of the University&amp;rsquo;s offices for Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion;
Academic Outreach; and Community Partnerships at UVA Health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementation of evidence-based, diversity-focused education programs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project senior personnel and student researchers will participate in the offerings and training provided by the University of Virginia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Division for Diversity, Equity and Inclusion office at the
University of Virginia offers training on education and prevention
related to discrimination and harassment, sexual misconduct,
mandated reporting, UVA System&amp;rsquo;s Equity and Title IX policies and
procedures, and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UVA requires employees to complete training in regard to its
Preventing and Addressing Discrimination, Harassment and
Retaliation (PADHR) and Title IX and Sexual Misconduct (Title IX)
policies and processes. New employees receive the training and are
required to complete it every two years. A separate training is
provided for employees in supervisory positions. These trainings
are aimed at ensuring every employee understands their rights and
responsibility with respect to discrimination, harassment,
retaliation and sexual misconduct, understands how to identify,
address and report potential prohibited conduct, how to intervene
as bystanders, and the process followed in response to a
complaint. Students also receive similar training with regard to
sexual misconduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UVA requires all employees to complete a &amp;ldquo;DEI and Cultural
Competence&amp;rdquo; learning module and offers more than 80 additional
DEI-related learning modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soliciting bids for supplies, services and equipment from minority owned, woman owned and veteran owned businesses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University is committed to: (1) enhancing successful business
relationships between small, minority-owned, women-owned, and
otherwise disadvantaged business enterprises (S/M/W/DBEs) and
through the implementation of programs that requires a consistent
and high level of participation from all University schools and
departments; and (2) actively seeking goods and services from
small, minority-owned, and women-owned businesses in support of
the Commonwealth&amp;rsquo;s small, minority-owned, and women-owned (SWaM)
program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Virginia increases business opportunities for
small, minority-owned, and women-owned business enterprises
(S/M/WBE&amp;rsquo;s) through its Supplier Diversity Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
