<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science FM Hub – cloudbank</title>
    <link>/tags/cloudbank/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cloudbank on Science FM Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/cloudbank/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Using Cloudbank</title>
      <link>/docs/tutorials/cloudbank/account/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/tutorials/cloudbank/account/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;using-cloudbank&#34;&gt;Using Cloudbank&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING&lt;/strong&gt;: ANY USE OF CLOUDBANK MUST INCLUDE THAT YOU HAVE A DEEP
UNDERSTANDING HOW CHARGES ARE DONE. WASTEFUL USE OF RESOURCES WHICH
COST REAL $ WILL RESULT IN AN IMMEDIATE TERMINATION OF YOUR
ACCOUNT. Any cost above $100 over the semester must be preapproved
and accompanied by a detailed cost breakdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students need to create an account on &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudbank.org&#34;&gt;https://cloudbank.org&lt;/a&gt; with
their university e-mail. Please follow the instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If multiple students need an account all students must have completed step 1 before we proceed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All names and emails as entered in Cloudbank must be forwarded to Gregor and Bud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activating-your-cloudbank-account-with-our-project&#34;&gt;Activating your Cloudbank account with our project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gregor will activate your Cloudbank account in the Cloudbank
project. You do not have to do anything but wait. Gregor will
notify Bud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bud will add you to AWS via Cloudbank. He will try to limit your
spending amount to $100 initially. You do not have to do
anything but wait.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bud will notify you and Gregor once this is done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This process is done on best effort and as we have never done it it
may take some time to complete. We anticipate a week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-to-do-while-you-wait&#34;&gt;What to do while you wait&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out which services you need on AWS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out what they cost as we have to pay for it in $ this needs to
be estimated precisely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it exceeds $100 you need to figure out why and estimate the total
cost over the entire semester as we do not have unlimited funds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you understand running costs and startup costs for a
service. Note: starting a service every second will cost a lot!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn that you must not place keys and certs in your
gitrepos. Figure out where to place them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you need ssh and use Windows use gitbash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve this tutorial and make pull pull request with your improvement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pitfalls&#34;&gt;Pitfalls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignore reading the documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not understanding ssh kegen, ssh agent, ssh-add&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Windows: Juts using putty and not understanding gitbash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Placeing any key in your project code other then reading them from a secure filesystem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not understanding what 1-4 is about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alternatives&#34;&gt;Alternatives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to use alternatives whenever you can&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spark is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rc.virginia.edu/userinfo/rivanna/software/spark/&#34;&gt;Rivanna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hadoop development can be done on Windows, Mac, Linux (Search in
google how to set it up). Development is often easier on your
laptop. Once you complete it use cloudbank.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MPI is available on Rivanna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TF and pytorch is available on Rivanna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jupyter notebooks can be run on Rivanna or Google Collab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;honor-policy&#34;&gt;Honor Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The project you do must be part of an approved project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must not use cloudbank and its clouds for personal projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must not use cloudbank and its clouds for bitcoin mining.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In case publications and reports be written based on usage form our
cloudbank account, you must include it in an Acknowledgement
statement and notify us with a copy of the report. Please note that
the report may be made publically available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
